Ever since Anthropic dropped the article
building effective agents, everyone's
been talking about agents and workflows.
Both agents and workflows are ways of
building more powerful things with LLMs.
And they both involve orchestrating
multiple calls to the LLM. A workflow
does this through predetermined steps
where you have one LM call which goes to
another call which goes to another call.
These predetermined steps are written in
code by the developer. And so the code
itself decides when to stop the program,
when to call the next LM. It's all
written into the code itself. An agent
though doesn't use predetermined steps.
It calls an LLM and gives it a bunch of
tools, different options of things that
it can do next. The LLM decides which
tool to call and then responds to the
result of those tools and then decides
itself when to stop the program when it
thinks it's finished. In other words,
this is the LLM making it up as it goes
along, which hands a lot more power to
the LLM, but of course makes it less
predictable. So, both agents and
workflows involve multiple LLM calls. If
you're just making one LLM call, it's
not really either of those things. But
the crucial difference is who decides
when to stop. With the agent, it's the
LLM. With the workflow, it's just
following a set of predetermined steps.
This means that agents are really good
in situations where the steps to
complete the task are not particularly
clear, where it needs the ability to
improvise, to figure out its way through
a difficult problem. But workflows are
great for things that need to be done
the same thing again and again and
again. And workflows are often unfairly
maligned because they're not as exciting
and sexy as agents. But you'll often get
better results from using a workflow
than using an agent as long as the task
is clearly specified. For instance, you
can use a workflow to parallelize work
where let's say we take in a chunk of
text. We can split it into two parts,
summarize each of them independently,
and then summarize the summaries
afterwards. So that's the difference
between agents and workflows. And I
don't know whether it's me being old and
boring, but I am more excited by
workflows than agents.